Council on the Continuing Education Unit (CCEU) Records
Council on the Continuing Education Unit (CCEU) Records
- Papers and Articles
  - About the CEU
    - Bastian, Lisa. "Close-Up on the CEU: The Tool Revolutionizing Education", 1997 (Box 23)
    - Baumann, Edward J. "Remarks", 1974 (Box 23)
    - Biedenbach, Joe. "The CEU Revisited", 1978 (Box 23)
    - Blume, Dorothy M. "Some Concerns Related to the Use of CEU", 1974 (Box 23)
    - Collins, Michael. "Some Further Thoughts on Principles of Good Practice in Continuing Education", 1985 (Box 23)
    - Committee for Professional Development. "CPD Committee Report to ASEE [American Society for Engineering Education]", 1978 (Box 23)
    - "Continuing Education Units: What Are They Really Worth?", 1982 (Box 23)
    - Darmstaetter, Josephine and Sanford, Robert. "The NFLPN CEU Data Bank Report: First Report", 1978 (Box 23)
      See also Correspondence-subject files: Other: CEU data bank proposal [John Rhodes files]
    - Darmstaetter, Josephine and Sanford, Robert. "The NFLPN CEU Data Bank Report, 1978", 1979 (Box 23)
    - de Porry, Andrew C. "The CEU: Implications for University Continuing Education", 1972 (Box 23)
    - Enell, John W. "The CEU Comes of Age", 1975 (Box 23)
    - Enell, John W. "Update on the Continuing Education Unit", 1978 (Box 23)
    - Enell, John W. "Getting Started with the CEU", undated, ca 1978 (Box 23)
    - Enell, John W. "Continuing Education, Certification, the Professional Engineer, and the CEU", 1979 (Box 23)
    - Enell, John W. "The CEU in the 1980s: A Report from a Long-Term User" (Box 23)
    - Enell, John W. "Did You Say 'CEU'?", 1980 (Box 23)
    - Florida Community College System. "The Implementation of the Continuing Education Unit in the Florida Community College System", undated, ca 1973 (Box 23)
    - Gallinot, Ruth, "CEU: What's In It For You?", 1981 (Box 23)
    - Gessner, Quentin H. "Continuing Education Unit", 1974 (Box 23)
    - Glancy, Keith E. "The CEU: A New Tool for Adult Educators", 1971 (Box 23)
    - Glancy, Keith E. "The Continuing Education Unit: A Progress Report", 1971 (Box 23)
    - Glancy, Keith E. "Counting Aardvarks and Zebras in Continuing Education", 1971 (Box 23)
    - Glancy, Keith E. "Excerpts from Pilot Program Evaluation Reports", 1971 (Box 24)
    - Glancy, Keith E. "A Permanent Record of Continuing Education Using the CE Unit", 1971 (Box 24)
    - Glancy, Keith E. "The CEU: Update", 1972 (Box 24)
    - Glancy, Keith E. "1975 Status Report on the Continuing Education Unit: Survey Summary" (Box 24)
    - Glancy, Keith E. "Introduction to the CEU", 1976 (Box 24)
    - Glancy, Keith E. "The CEU Revisited", 1980 (Box 24)
    - Glancy, Keith E. "Introduction to the CEU" (2d Annual Conference address), 1980 (Box 24)
    - Glancy, Keith E. "Introduction to the CEU" (3rd Annual Conference address), 1981 (Box 24)
    - Glancy, Keith E. "Introduction to the CEU" (4th Annual Conference address), 1982 (Box 24)
    - Glancy, Keith E. and Courtney, Margaret E. "Continuing Education: Problems and Progress", 1974 (Box 24)
    - Glancy, Keith E. and Courtney, Margaret E. "Making Sense Out of the CEU", 1974 (Box 24)
    - Glancy, Keith E. and Courtney, Margaret E. "Recording Education with the CEU", 1974 (Box 24)
    - Glancy, Keith E. and Rhodes, John A. Jr. "CEU Criteria and Guidelines: Excerpts", undated (Box 24)
    - Greenwald, Stanley. "ASME [Association of Mechanical Engineers] Adopts the CEU", 1977 (Box 24)
    - Griffith, Dean E. "Use of the CEUs by Industry", 1979 (Box 24)
    - Grogan, Paul J. "Continuing Education Comes of Age", 1968 (Box 24)
    - Grogan, Paul J. "Recommendation: Establish a Credit Norm for Continuing Education", 1970 (Box 24)
    - Grogan, Paul J. "The Continuing Education Unit", 1971 (Box 24)
    - Grogan, Paul J. "Introducing the Continuing Education Unit", 1971 (Box 24)
    - Grogan, Paul J. "The Concept of a Continuing Education Unit", 1972 (Box 24)
    - Grogan, Paul J. "Q: New Concepts in Packaging Continuing Education", 1972 (Box 24)
    - Grogan, Paul J. "The Continuing Education Unit: Future of the CEU", 1973 (Box 24)
    - Grogan, Paul J. "Continuing Education for the Professions", 1974 (Box 24)
    - Grogan, Paul J. "The Continuing Education Unit: Its Role in Continuing Education and Professional Development", 1974 (Box 24)
    - Grogan, Paul J. "CEU: A Perspective on Its Purposes and Prospects", 1976 (Box 24)
    - Grogan, Paul J. "Introducing the Continuing Education Unit: Its Implications for Business and Industry", 1976 (Box 24)
    - Grogan, Paul J. "Continuing Education and the CEU", 1979 (Box 24)
    - Grogan, Paul J. "Evaluation and Use of Continuing Education for Recognition Purposes", 1980 (Box 24)
    - Grogan, Paul J. "Suggestions for a Program of Action Concerning the Continuing Education Unit", undated (Box 24)
    - Gross, Ronald. "Controlling Quality: Can It Be Done?", 1984 (Box 24)
    - Gwaltney, Betty. "The Continuing Education Unit", 1973 (Box 24)
    - Hannon, James P. "Continuing Professional Education for a CPA Firm", 1980 (Box 24)
    - Helms, Lawrence. "CEU Can Be Important Element in Meeting Package", 1981 (Box 24)
    - Houle, Cyril O. "The Evaluation of Continuing Professional Education", 1980 (Box 24)
    - Hulbert, Dan. "The CEU: What's Its Credit Rating?", 1979 (Box 24)
    - Hutchinson, Dorothy J. "Credit for Non-Credit?", 1971 (Box 24)
    - Illinois Community College Board. "Continuing Education Unit: Selected Conference Proceedings", 1974 (Box 24)
    - Iowa State Coordinating Committee for Continuing Education. "A System for Recording and Awarding Continuing Education Units on Non-Credit Continuing Education CEUs...", 1973 (Box 24)
    - Jesse, Glen D. "The Continuing Education Unit", 1973 (Box 24)
    - Jones, Alden M. "The Continuing Education Unit: A View From Industry", 1975 (Box 24)
    - Kempfer, Homer. "Beulah Ashbrook on the CEU", 1978 (Box 24)
    - Kempfer, Homer and Day, Michael. "CEU Credit for Adults: Pro and Con", 1983 (Box 24)
    - Kutler, Gordon E. "CEU: A Giant Step Backward", 1975 (Box 24)
    - Lindberg, David S. "I.E.U. - C.E.U.", 1973 (Box 24)
      See also Correspondence-subject files: Other: Individual Education Account [William L. Turner files]
    - Medical and Chirurgical Faculty of the State of Maryland. "Continuing Education Unit: A Concept for Uniformity", undated, ca 1970 (Box 24)
    - Miller, Jerry W. "The CEU and Educational Alternatives", 1975 (Box 24)
    - National Center for Education Statistics. "Noncredit Activities in Institutions of Higher Education", 1976 (Box 24)
    - National Center for Education Statistics. "Adult and Continuing Education in Colleges and Universities", 1979 (Box 25)
    - National League for Nursing. "NLN's Role in Continuing Education in Nursing", 1973 (Box 25)
    - National University Extension Association. "The Imminent National Implementation of the CEU", 1973 (Box 25)
    - Nelton, Sharon. "Education: Keeping Current", 1981 (Box 25)
    - Ohio University. "National Registry Maintains CE Records", 1980 (Box 25)
    - "The Continuing Education Unit", 1979 (Box 25)
    - Phillips, Louis E. (ed.) "The Continuing Education Unit: A Compilation of Selected Readings", 1972 (Box 25)
    - Phillips, Louis E. (ed.) "The Continuing Education Unit: Implications for Record Keeping", 1972 (Box 25)
    - Phillips, Louis E. (ed.) "The Continuing Education Unit: A New Dimension in Lifelong Learning", 1974 (Box 25)
    - Phillips, Louis E. (ed.) "The Continuing Education Unit: A New Dimension in Continuing Education", 1976 (Box 25)
    - Phillips, Louis E. (ed.) "The Continuing Education Guide: The CEU and Other Professional Development Criteria", 1994 (Box 25)
    - Pitchell, Robert J. "Criteria for the Handbook", 1972 (Box 25)
    - Reuss, Henry S. "Industrial Policy", 1983 (Box 25)
    - Reyes-Guerra, David and Lawrence D. Maloney. "There Are Still a Lot of Charlatans in the Marketplace", 1987 (Box 25)
    - Shelton, Howard. "The CEU in the 1980s: A Report From a Current Non-User" (Box 25)
    - Simon, Carol. "All About CEUs #15", 1982 (Box 25)
    - Snarponis, Joseph M. and Donald Weinart. "Concept Paper for a National Professional Development Registry for Engineers", 1979 (Box 25)
    - Southern Association of Colleges and Schools. "Standards of the College Delegate Assembly", 1972 (Box 25)
    - Southern Association of Colleges and Schools. "The Continuing Education Unit Guidelines and Other Information", 1973 (Box 25)
    - Southern Association of Colleges and Schools. "The Continuing Education Unit Guidelines and Other Information, 2d edition", 1980 (Box 25)
    - Southern Regional Education Board. "Questions and Answers About the Continuing Education Unit", undated (Box 25)
    - Sparks, Jim. "Relevance of the CEU to Clergy Continuing Education", 1975 (Box 25)
    - State Council of Higher Education for Virginia. "Coordination of Higher Education", 1972 (Box 25)
    - State Council of Higher Education for Virginia. "Instructions for Public Service Offerings", 1973 (Box 25)
    - Tilton, Steven R. "CEU Guidelines", 1981 (Box 25)
    - Turner, William L. "Role of the National Task Force", 1972 (Box 25)
    - Turner, William L. "An Update on the Continuing Education Unit", 1973 (Box 25)
    - University of South Dakota. "The CEU: A Trend in Continuing Education", 1973 (Box 25)
    - University of South Florida. "Development of a System for Recording Continuing Education Units", 1972 (Box 25)
    - University of Wisconsin. "A Proposal for the Utilization and Implementation of the Continuing Education Unit (CEU) in University Extension", 1971 (Box 25)
    - University System of Georgia. "Continuing Education and Public Service Record Keeping", 1972 (Box 25)
    - University System of Georgia. "Utilization of the Continuing Education Unit (CEU) Within the University System of Georgia", 1973 (Box 25)
    - Virginia Polytechnic Institute and University. "General Information on the Continuing Education Unit", 1972 (Box 25)
    - Watkins, Beverly T. "Continuing Education Unit Gains as Measure of Non-Credit Study", 1979 (Box 25)
  - Other topics
    - Alford, Harold J. "Power and Conflict in Continuing Education" (abstract), undated (Box 26)
    - Andrews, Grover J. "Accreditation of Adult Education Programs in Higher Education", 1972 (Box 26)
    - Andrews, Grover J. "Accreditation of Adult Education Programs in Higher Education", 1973 (Box 26)
    - Andrews, Grover J. "Guidelines for the Use and Application of Standard IX in the Self-Study Process for Colleges and Universities", 1974 (Box 26)
    - Cervero, Ronald M. "Collaboration in University Continuing Professional Education", 1985 (Box 26)
    - Educational Testing Service. "Educational Passport", 1981 (Box 26)
    - Fannon, Pete J. "A Rationale for Obtaining General Revenue Support for Certain State University System Non-Credit Instructional Activities", 1972 (Box 26)
    - Ferry, Robert A. "Tests in Adult Non-Credit Education", 1979 (Box 26)
    - Glancy, Keith E. "Professionalism in Adult and Continuing Education", 1972 (Box 26)
    - Holt, Margaret E. and Bradley C. Courtenay. "An Examination of Impact Evaluations", 1986 (Box 26)
    - Katz, Israel and Paul J. Grogan. "Evolving Concepts of Continuing Engineering Studies", 1971 (Box 26)
    - Morris, Albert J. "Is Continuing Education Worth the Effort?", 1979 (Box 26)
    - Nassar, Esam M. "Quality Assurance in Continuing Professional Education", 1983 (Box 26)
    - National Education Goals Panel. "The National Education Goals Report: Building a Nation of Learners", 1992 (Box 26)
    - Phillips, Louis E. "The Status of Mandatory Continuing Education for the Professions", 1977 (Box 26)
    - Schweer, Jean E. "The Name of the Game", 1974 (Box 26)
    - Southern Association of Colleges and Schools. "Accreditation in Adult and Continuing Education Programs", 1973 (Box 26)
    - Sparks, Howard. "Continuing Education: A Central Concern", 1985 (Box 26)
    - University System of Georgia. "Financial Program for Higher Education in Georgia", 1969 (Box 26)
- Principles and Practices
  - American Association of Collegiate Registrars and Admissions Officers (Box 26)
  - American Bankers Association (Box 26)
  - American College Testing Program (Box 26)
  - American Hospital Association (Box 26)
  - American Management Associations (Box 26)
  - American Physical Therapy Association of Maryland (Box 26)
  - American Public Power Association (Box 26)
  - American Society for Medical Technology (Box 26)
  - American Speech-Language-Hearing Association (Box 26)
  - Arizona State Nurses Association (Box 26)
  - Association of Cytogenetic Technologists (Box 26)
  - Bank Administration Institute (Box 26)
  - Boy Scouts of America (Box 26)
  - Daughters of Charity Health System (Box 26)
  - Dundalk Community College (Box 26)
  - Emma L. Bixby Hospital (Box 26)
  - Fayetteville Area Health Education Foundation (Box 26)
  - Hazelden Training and Professional Education (Box 26)
  - Health Education Foundation of Eastern North Carolina (Box 26)
  - Illinois Statewide CEU Task Force (Box 26)
  - Indiana University (Box 26)
  - International Association of Electrical Inspectors (Box 26)
  - Iowa State Coordinating Committee for Continuing Education (Box 26)
  - Michigan State University (Box 26)
  - Mississippi State University (Box 26)
  - Missouri Nurses Association (Box 26)
  - Montclair State College (Box 26)
  - National Federation of Licensed Practical Nurses (Box 26)
  - National League for Nursing (Box 26)
  - North Carolina Department of Community Colleges (Box 27)
  - North Carolina State University (Box 27)
  - Ohio Department of Education (Box 27)
  - Ordre des Ingenieurs du Quebec (Box 27)
  - Pennsylvania State University (Box 27)
  - Philmont Volunteer Training Center (Box 27)
  - Professional Secretaries International (Box 27)
  - Purdue University (Box 27)
  - Queens College (Box 27)
  - Southwest Research Institute (Box 27)
  - Texas (State of) (Box 27)
  - Texas Christian University (Box 27)
  - University of Alabama (Box 27)
  - University of Colorado (Box 27)
  - University of Delaware (Box 27)
  - University of North Carolina (Box 27)
  - University of Victoria (Box 27)
  - University of Wisconsin (Box 27)
  - Wausau State Hospital (Box 27)
  - Wayne County Intermediate School District (Box 27)
  - West Virginia University (Box 27)
  - Whirlpool Corporation (Box 27)
- Proceedings
  - The Continuing Education Unit: An Examination (Proceedings of a National Conference on the Continuing Education Unit, 1972 Apr (Box 27)
  - Proceedings of the Tennessee Workshop on Standard IX and the CEU, 1974 May (Box 27)
    See also Correspondence-subject files: Other: Tennessee Workshop on Standard IX and the CEU [John Rhodes files]
  - An Invitational Conference on Continuing Education for Health Professionals, 1978 Mar (Box 27)
  - National Invitational Conference on Continuing Education for Allied Health Professionals, 1978 Sep (Box 27)
    See also Meetings and minutes: Other meetings and presentations: National Invitational Conference on Continuing Education for Allied Health Professions
  - First Annual Conference of the Council on the Continuing Education Unit, 1979 Jun (Box 27)
  - Second Annual Conference of the Council on the Continuing Education Unit, 1980 Jun (Box 27)
  - Third Annual Conference of the Council on the Continuing Education Unit, 1981 Jun (Box 28)
    See also Meetings and minutes: Other meetings and presentations: CCEU 3rd Annual Conference
  - Fourth Annual Conference of the Council on the Continuing Education Unit, 1982 Jun (Box 28)
    See also Meetings and minutes: Other meetings and presentations: CCEU 4th Annual Conference
  - Fifth Annual Conference of the Council on the Continuing Education Unit, 1983 Jun (Box 28)
    See also Meetings and minutes: Other meetings and presentations: CCEU 5th Annual Conference
- Research reports
  - Cervero, Ronald M. "Analyzing the Effectiveness of Continuing Professional Education", Nov 1984 (Box 28)
  - Corkery, Ellen M. "Mandatory Continuing Education in the Nursing Profession: Four States' Experience", May 1986 (Box 28)
  - Georgia Center for Continuing Education. "A Special Report to the National Task Force on the Continuing Education Unit", May 1973 (Box 28)
  - Leahy, Robert F. "Higher Education's Utilization of the Continuing Education Unit: A Mechanism for Recording Lifelong Learning", Dec 1974 (Box 28)
  - Podurgiel, Madelaine. "Impact of Continuing Education Workshops on Professional Behavior", Sep 1986 (Box 28)
- Miscellaneous
  - Continuing education brochures (various) (Box 28)
  - Continuing education unit (CEU) brochures (various) (Box 28)
  - Dissertations
    - House, Richard M. (North Carolina State University) "Standards of Practice in Continuing Education: A Status Study", 1983 (Box 29)
    - Leiter, Robert B. (University of Cincinnati) "Perceptions of the Continuing Education Unit by Participants Enrolled in Non-credit Activities", 1983 (Box 29)
    - Mitchell, Joan Kirchman Parsons (University of Alabama) "The Continuing Education Unit 1967-1977: A Decade in Review", 1981 (Box 29)
    - Phillips, Louis Edwin (University of Georgia) "A Study of the Uses and Effects of the Continuing Education Unit Within Selected User Groups", 1973 (Box 29)